

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Passionate about utilizing software engineering, decision making, and communicating stories within the tech sector. I am an action oriented team player and leader with experience in tackling complex missions, working with diverse people, and planning at strategic levels.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End:

React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3

Back-End:

Node, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Passport, Socket.IP, Ruby on Rails, RESTful Services

Languages:

JavaScript, Ruby

Database Management:

Mongo DB, PostgreSQL, Mongoose, SQL, SQLite3

Deployment Tools:

Webpack, Git, Bash, Babel, Postman, VS Code, AWS, Heroku

OPERATIONAL LEADERSHIP

MANAGEMENT:

Project Management, Team Leadership, Training, Critical and Analytical Thinking, Decision Making, Adaptability, Interagency Coordination, Writing, Negotiation and Mediation, Relationship Building, Customer Resource Management, Microsoft Suite

CONTACT DETAILS

\((347) 613-2562

gigimscarborough@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/gigimscarborough/
github.com/gigimscarborough

GIGI SCARBOROUGH

Software Engineer

PROJECTS

FULLPLATE Live Site | GitHub

An Open Table Clone that allows users to manage restaurant reservations built using a Rails Backend and a React / Redux frontend

- Technology Used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, jBuilder, React and Redux, PostgreSQL
- Created modals to handle frontend user authentication and search functionality, ensuring a modern, streamlined user experience
- Employed RESTful API to allow guests to seamlessly interface with the app's various features and persist user selections throughout while curating a single-page app experience
- Built dynamic search functionality by designing a custom Rails backend route and a distinct React UI reducer to improve search performance and flexibility

FIT2ME Live Site | GitHub

A fitness app that connects fitness seekers to trainers affording them flexibility of their choice of location created with MERN stack

- <u>Technology Used:</u> MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Express.js, React
- Guided and designed the construction of the app from conception to inception resulting in a seamless integration between frontend and backend technologies and a user interface that is both functionally optimized and aesthetically pleasing
- Managed scheduling and booking CRUD through custom transactional database operations using MongoDB and ExpressJS resulting in more accurate and efficient reservation creation

COCO CRAZE Live Site | GitHub

A fun game created with HTML Canvas , CSS, and Javascript where players can score points by catching falling objects in the basket

- Technology Used: Vanilla Javascript, HTML Canvas, CSS
- Applied HTML and Vanilla Javascript to create eye-catching transitions designed to keep the player engaged and integrate game flow.
- Leveraged the asynchronous nature of Javascript to fashion gameplay animations that operate harmoniously and in conjunction with transitional elements.
- Handled HTML Canvas dynamic frame rate to ensure smooth gameplay as the complexity increases with each level

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bunny VIP Liason

Playboy Club NYC | 2019 - 2020

- Managed and initiated member outreach that resulted in increases in 5 to 7% membership purchases and events bookings as well as overall member and customer satisfaction
- Conceptualized and coordinated events that boosted company visibility, branding, marketing, and influence
- Consistently employed best practices to prevent revenue loss while also leading the staff in sales by bringing in an average of \$10,000 in revenue weekly resulting in an annual net of around \$500,000 annually

VIP Experience Coordinator

Hudson Terrace | 2015 - 2020

- Consistently met and exceeded company goals for experiences booked and average guest spending by employing innovative customer service and up-selling techniques.
- Pioneered and spearheaded customer relationship strategies to boost overall client satisfaction while acting as a representative agent between clients and upper management
- Trained, supported, and led new hires in effective tactics to increase guest consumption and retention, resulting in a 20% increase in repeat client bookings, in addition to overseeing a selection of operational procedures

EDUCATION

Software Development Engineering

App Academy (New York, New York) | 2020 - 2021

Relevant Coursework: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, Webpack, jQuery, Git, Heroku, RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine, Jest, Test-Driven Development (TDD), Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Data Structures and Algorithms

Broadcast Journalism

Hofstra University | 2011

Relevant Coursework: Media, Communications, Public Relations, Digital Storytelling, News Writing and Reporting, Mulltimedia Journalism

Extracurriculars: Black Student Union

High School Diploma

St. John's Preparatory School | 2007